Guide to Lorcan Folan Papers RG.044
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Lorcan Folan Papers
1973-2020
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Folan, Lorcan, M. (Lorcan Michael), 1960-
RG.044
3 Linear Feet
Biographical / Historical
Lorcan Folan was an Applied Physics Professor and Department Chair at the NYU Tandon School of Engineering. He received his Doctor of Philosophy in Physics from Polytechnic University.
Scope and Contents
The Lorcan Folan Papers contain documents from 1973 to 2020. These documents were assembled by Folan throughout his time as Department Chair of the Physics Department. Most documents are of significance to multiple departments, including information on committees, financials, and more. Additionally, there are course catalogs, curriculum development plans, and documents on the NYU-Poly Merger. The collection is 3 linear feet, located on bay 29, shelves 6C and 7C.
Arrangement
This collection is housed in six boxes and arranged into eight series:
Series I: Faculty Committees, 2004-2020 Series II: Polytechnic Financial Documents, 1986-2009 Series III: Nuclear, 2010 Series IV: Curriculum, 1992-2006 Series V: NYU-Poly Merger, 1973-2007 Series VI: Miscellaneous University Documents, 1989-2005 Series VII: Course Catalogs, 1990-2003 Series VIII: Accreditations, 1994-2013
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated to the Polytechnic Institute of New York University Archives by Lorcan Folan in 2020.
Physics; Polytechnic University (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).
- Series I: Faculty Committees, 2004-2020
  Scope and Contents
  The Faculty Committees series of the Lorcan Folan Papers contains documents pertaining to the Undergraduate Curriculum and Standards Committee, the Graduate Curriculum and Standards Committee, the Federal Election Commission, and more.
  - UGCSC 04-05, 2004-2005; 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - UGCSC 2005-06, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - UGCSC 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - UGCSC 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - UGCSC 09-10, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - UGCSC '10-'11, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - UGCSC 2011-12, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - UGCSC 2012-13, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - UGCSC 2013/14, 2013-2014 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - UGCSC 2014-15, 2014-2015 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - UGCSC 2015-16, 2015-2016 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - UGCSC 2016-17, 2016-2017 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - UGCSC 2017-19, 2017-2019 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - UGCSC 2019- (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - UG Experience Committee, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Elections, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Assessment, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ABET, 2020 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - FEC 2005-06, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - FEC 2006-07, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - FEC 2007-08, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - FEC 2008-09, 2008-2009 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - FEC 09-10, 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - FEC 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - FEC 2011-12, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - FEC 2012-13, 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - FEC 2013/14, 2013-2014 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - FEC 2014-15, 2014-2015 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - FEC 2015-16, 2015-2016 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - FEC 2016-17, 2016-2017 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - FEC 2017-19, 2017-2019 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - FEC 2019- (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - CEC, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - GCSC, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Blank, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - GCSC '16-'17, 2016-2017 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - GCSC 2017-19, 2017-2019 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - GCSC 19-, 2019 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Affirmative Action, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Conflict Resolution, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - ABET 2014 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Calendar Committee, 2016 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Architect's Committee, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - ABET Visit, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Series II: Polytechnic Financial Documents, 1986-2009
  The Polytechnic Financial Documents series of the Lorcan Folan Papers contains financial documents about Polytechnic from 1986-2009.
  - Financial Statements, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - FIC, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Physics Department Annual Reports and Maxwell Correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Series III: Nuclear, 2010
  The Nuclear series of the Lorcan Folan Papers contains information about nuclear waste disposal at Polytechnic University.
  - Disposal, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series IV: Curriculum, 1992-2006
  The Curriculum series of the Lorcan Folan Papers contains information about study abroad programs, graduate curriculum, and course information beyond the physics department.
  - Studs From Greece, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Core, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Course Numbers, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - UCC Articulation, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Clean Slate, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dean's Forum, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Grad Curr Stan, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Digital Media, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum Stuff, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Series V: NYU-Poly Merger, 1973-2007
  The NYU-Poly Merger series of the Lorcan Folan Papers contains information about the potential and later fully realized merger of NYU and Polytechnic University.
  - Blank, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - POLY-NYU, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - NYU Merger, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series VI: Miscellaneous University Documents, 1989-2005
  The Miscellaneous University Documents series of the Lorcan Folan Papers contains information about various projects and events at Polytechnic University.
  - Poly News Spring 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Pratt, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Articulation, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Polytechnic University Year 2000 Compliance Project (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Official Documents of Polytechnic University January 2005 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Appreciative Inquiry Summit for Polytechnic University, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Drawing a Picture of Our Future, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - A Case for i^2e, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Code of Conduct, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Series VII: Course Catalogs, 1990-2003
  The Course Catalogs series of the Lorcan Folan Papers includes course catalogs from each semester from 1990-2003.
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Summer 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Summer 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 1994 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Summer 1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1994 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Summer 1995 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1995 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Summer 1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1996 Early Edition (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1996 Second Edition (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1996 Second Edition (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 1997 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Summer 1997 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1997 Early Edition (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1997 Second Edition (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 1998 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Summer 1998 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1998 Early Edition (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 1999 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Summer 1999 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1999 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 1999 Early Edition (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 2000 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Summer 2000 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 2000 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 2001 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Summer 2001 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 2002 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Summer 2002 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Fall 2002 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Polytechnic University Schedule of Classes Spring 2003 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Series VIII: Accreditations, 1994-2013
  The Accreditations series of the Lorcan Folan Papers includes various documents about different university accrediations, including MSA and MSCHE, from 1994-2013.
  - Interim Report: Program: Bachelor of Science (Civil Engineering) Polytechnic University, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Report for Interim Visit: Program in Mechanical Engineering, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - MSCHE 2013 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - MSCHE 2008 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Monitoring Report to the Middle States Commission on Higher Education from Polytechnic University, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Polytechnic University Self-Study Report, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Middle States Commission on Higher Education, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Characteristics of Excellence in Higher Education, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Designs for Excellence: Handbook for Institutional Self-Study, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - MSA Annual + Other Reports, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Middle States '13, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Middle States '11, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - MSA Correspondance, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Accreditation Other, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 19)